<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Godot Engine Official</title><link/><description/><atom:link href="https://godotengine.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ensuring quality in the Godot documentation, a continuous process</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/</link><summary>The Godot documentation is the fruits of the labor of hundreds of people working together. How do we ensure the highest possible level of quality, while making it easy for anyone to contribute? Find out in this article.</summary><description>&lt;p>What makes up the quality and usability of an open-source project is not just about its code. A big part of what makes a project useful to the community is its documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, Godot contributors have developed many tools and processes to ensure the highest possible level of quality for the &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/">documentation&lt;/a>. Read on if you’re curious about how the documentation is made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="documentation-repository-organization">Documentation repository organization&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot’s documentation is hosted on &lt;a href="https://about.readthedocs.com/">Read the Docs&lt;/a>. This service provides hosting for projects using &lt;a href="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">Sphinx&lt;/a>, which is a static site generator targeted at building documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The documentation’s source files are hosted &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs">on GitHub&lt;/a>. Several customizations have been made to improve readability, such as &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/_static/css/custom.css">adding a dark theme&lt;/a> (used according to browser/OS preferences) and &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/_extensions/gdscript.py">GDScript syntax highlighting&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a continuous integration system in place, which performs several automated tasks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/.github/workflows/ci.yml">General continuous integration&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Runs pre-commit hooks and builds the website to ensure no errors occur. The pre-commit hooks are configured to check for typos using &lt;a href="https://github.com/codespell-project/codespell">codespell&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/.github/workflows/sync_class_ref.yml">Synchronize the class reference&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automatically synchronizes the generated class reference with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/tree/master/doc/classes">class reference XML&lt;/a> from the main Godot repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/.github/workflows/build_offline_docs.yml">Build offline documentation in HTML and ePub formats&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Creates downloads of the documentation in offline-friendly formats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/.github/workflows/check_urls.yml">Check URLs for dead links&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URLs can stop working over time for several reasons. This check makes it possible to be informed of link rot and replace links with archived versions when needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/blob/master/.github/workflows/cherrypick.yml">Automatically cherry-pick relevant pull requests to stable branches&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The documentation is split into several branches (one for &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master&lt;/code>, one for the latest &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stable&lt;/code> version, one for &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.3&lt;/code> and so on). Pull requests that make changes relevant for stable versions are assigned a label such as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cherrypick:4.3&lt;/code>. When the pull request is merged, the commit is automatically cherry-picked to the corresponding stable branch.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="internationalizing-the-documentation">Internationalizing the documentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the Godot community is worldwide, we want the ability to provide not only the Godot editor in users’ native languages, but also the documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To internationalize content that gets continuously updated, we use dedicated tooling to keep the translations in sync with the source material. Sphinx can extract content from each page to put in translation catalogs in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gettext">Gettext&lt;/a> format (POT/PO files, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/en/stable/tutorials/i18n/localization_using_gettext.html">also supported by Godot!&lt;/a>). We merge these 500 POT files into a monolithic “Godot Documentation” component (500,000 words).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The class reference is handled separately as its source material is not Sphinx’s reStructuredText files, but XML files in the engine repository. For this, we use &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-editor-l10n/blob/main/scripts/extract_classes.py">a script&lt;/a> to extract the descriptions from the XML files and generate a Gettext POT file (600,000 words).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we’re currently at 1,100,000 words of documentation to translate! To put this into perspective, the Godot editor’s translation has a bit more than 40,000 words.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Godot uses &lt;a href="https://hosted.weblate.org">Hosted Weblate&lt;/a> as a collaborative translation platform. This greatly simplifies the barrier to entry for editing Gettext files without merge conflicts, and provides a number of additional features such as suggestions, translation memory, or the ability to cross-compare translations.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/godot-engine/godot-docs/">&lt;strong>Godot Documentation&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/godot-engine/godot-class-reference/">&lt;strong>Class Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> components on Hosted Weblate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Localized documentation websites: &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/cs/4.x/">cs&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/de/4.x/">de&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/es/4.x/">es&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/fr/4.x/">fr&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/it/4.x/">it&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/ja/4.x/">ja&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/ko/4.x/">ko&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/pl/4.x/">pl&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/pt-br/4.x/">pt-br&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/ru/4.x/">ru&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/uk/4.x/">uk&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/zh-cn/4.x/">zh-cn&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/zh-tw/4.x/">zh-tw&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://contributing.godotengine.org/en/latest/documentation/translation/index.html">Documentation on contributing translations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://chat.godotengine.org/channel/translation">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#translation&lt;/code> channel on the Godot Contributors Chat&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Hosted Weblate Godot documentation website screenshot" src="/storage/blog/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/hosted-weblate.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="splitting-the-contributor-documentation-to-its-own-website">Splitting the contributor documentation to its own website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since September 2025, documentation for new and returning engine contributors has been split to its own website, &lt;a href="https://contributing.godotengine.org">contributing.godotengine.org&lt;/a>. This website is powered by Sphinx, just like the main documentation. This split was motivated by several factors:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The documentation is split by minor version, but the contributing documentation generally does not need a version split. Feature development always happens on the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master&lt;/code> branch, with cherry-picking towards the previous stable branch. In practice, it’s easier to maintain only one version of the documentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contributing to the engine requires English reading comprehension. The existing documentation had some translations available, but they were not always complete or up-to-date. Focusing on English for contribution guides reduces the burden on translators, which can then better focus on other sections of the manual.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note that some of the pages that were previously in the Contributing section of the documentation were moved to a new section called &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/en/latest/engine_details/architecture/index.html">Engine details&lt;/a>. These pages are not just useful for engine contributors, but also for people looking to compile their own builds and write custom modules in C++.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an aside, splitting this website allows it to build much faster, which is useful when testing changes locally. The main documentation website now also builds slightly faster, but is still slow due to containing the class reference. The GitHub repository for the new website can be found at &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-contributing-docs">godotengine/godot-contributing-docs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="class-reference-progress-tracker">Class reference progress tracker&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Godot documentation is more than just a manual. It also contains an hosted mirror of the &lt;em>class reference&lt;/em>, which documents every class that’s exposed to the scripting API in the engine. This class reference can be read directly offline in the editor, but the hosted version can be linked to on a website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the class reference represents a massive amount of items to document, we built a website to track the documentation progress for each class:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/doc-status/">&lt;strong>Godot class reference status&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This website relies on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/doc/tools/doc_status.py">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">doc_status.py&lt;/code>&lt;/a> script from the main Godot repository, which detects the completion percentage and outputs a Markdown table with the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being aware of the overall and per-class completion percentages at all times made it a lot easier to improve the documentation coverage. As of writing, the overall completion percentage is &lt;strong>97%&lt;/strong>. With additional efforts from &lt;a href="https://contributing.godotengine.org/en/latest/documentation/class_reference.html">contributors like you&lt;/a>, we can perhaps reach 100% completion in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Godot class reference status website screenshot" src="/storage/blog/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/doc-status.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="team-reports-for-class-reference-pull-requests">Team reports for class reference pull requests&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another way for contributors to organize pull requests and work through the backlog is to use the &lt;em>team reports&lt;/em> website. This website was built for contributors to check all open pull requests in a more convenient fashion than using GitHub’s web interface. Using this website, it’s easier to see when pull requets were last active and whether they are in a mergeable state (which may not be the case due to merge conflicts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This website only tracks the main Godot repository on GitHub, not the documentation repository. With that said, in the context of the documentation, this is still relevant since all contributions to the class reference are sent to the main Godot repository. (The documentation repository only hosts a generated copy of the class reference from the XML source files.)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-team-reports/#documentation">&lt;strong>Godot Team Reports&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Godot team reports website screenshot" src="/storage/blog/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/team-reports.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="user-notes-system">User notes system&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2024, the Godot documentation got an integration for user notes using &lt;a href="https://giscus.app/">Giscus&lt;/a>. This allows users to share additional information relevant for documentation readers. This integration is currently present on the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.4&lt;/code>, &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5&lt;/code>, &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stable&lt;/code>, and &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">latest&lt;/code> branches of the documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, you can see it in action at the bottom of the &lt;a href="https://docs.godotengine.org/en/stable/tutorials/scripting/gdscript/gdscript_basics.html#godot-giscus">GDScript reference&lt;/a> manual page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Godot documentation user notes screenshot" src="/storage/blog/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/user-notes.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-have-user-notes-on-the-documentation">Why have user notes on the documentation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Godot documentation is an essential learning resource for new and returning users alike. However, the content can sometimes benefit from additional clarification not found on the page itself. Since it’s an officially-maintained resource, it also tries to limit the number of third-party resources it links to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To resolve this problem, we’ve decided to introduce a &lt;em>user note system&lt;/em> in the Godot documentation. Inspired by user-provided comment systems such as &lt;a href="https://www.php.net/docs.php">PHP’s&lt;/a>, this allows the community to make the documentation more useful for everyone: not just for users, but also for engine developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It should be noted that &lt;em>user notes&lt;/em> are different from the usual comments you’d find on a blog post.&lt;/strong> As described by the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs-user-notes/discussions/1">user-contributed notes policy&lt;/a>, they are intended to be used to provide additional context for the documentation or link to community resources. They are not designed to report bugs or suggest features. When the documentation is incorrect or outdated, please open an issue on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs">godot-docs&lt;/a> repository instead of leaving a user note.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-user-notes-are-implemented">How user notes are implemented&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The user notes integration is powered by &lt;a href="https://giscus.app/">Giscus&lt;/a>, an open-source script that allows integrating a GitHub Discussions thread on a web page. To do so, it automatically creates a discussion in a &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs-user-notes">repository&lt;/a> when the first comment on a page is posted. On the Godot documentation, pages are matched based on their file name, but several page matching modes are provided by Giscus depending on the website’s needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being hosted on GitHub Discussions allows anyone with a GitHub account to comment. On the organizational side, this also reduces system administration overhead as no separate backend or database for hosting comments is required. Spam protection (a traditionally difficult topic with comment platforms) is handled on GitHub’s end, which has historically been quite effective at avoiding spam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a bonus, you can also watch the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs-user-notes">godot-docs-user-notes&lt;/a> repository on GitHub to be informed of new user notes being added to documentation pages. Replying to user notes left by others is a good way to get started with documentation improvements, as many user notes bring new information that can be incorporated into the main page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This organization allows more people to contribute in various ways, even with limited technical know-how. Not only does the documentation benefit from those opening &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/pulls">pull requests&lt;/a>, it’s also continuously improved every day by those posting user notes at the bottom of documentation pages. These user notes bring further clarifications and context to the manual pages, as well as linking to useful resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A massive &lt;strong>thank you&lt;/strong> to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-docs/graphs/contributors">all contributors to the documentation&lt;/a>! As always, we welcome contributions to the documentation. &lt;a href="https://contributing.godotengine.org/en/latest/documentation/overview.html">The contribution process is well-documented&lt;/a>, but you’re welcome to hop on the &lt;a href="https://chat.godotengine.org/channel/documentation">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#documentation&lt;/code> channel on the Godot Contributors Chat&lt;/a> if you have any questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you would like to help with the development of these features, please consider &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">supporting the project financially&lt;/a>! More funding allows us to sponsor volunteer contributors and better respond to technical demands of project users.&lt;/p></description><category>News</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation/</guid><dc:creator>Hugo Locurcio</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/ensuring-quality-godot-documentation.webp</image></item><item><title>Godot 4.5, making dreams accessible</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-4-5-making-dreams-accessible/</link><summary>From mind-blowing effects now made possible by the stencil buffer to accessibilty descriptions of your GUI elements that opens up the possibility for some with disabilities to play your game — we are proud to present to you Godot 4.5.</summary><description/><category>Release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-4-5-making-dreams-accessible/</guid><dc:creator>Godot contributors</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/godot-4-5-making-dreams-accessible.webp?cache=v2</image></item><item><title>Release candidate: Godot 4.5 RC 2</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-2/</link><summary>One more for the road, again!</summary><description>&lt;p>On Friday of last week, we dropped our first &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle#Release_candidate">Release Candidate&lt;/a> build. As a reminder, we release RC builds once we &lt;em>think&lt;/em> the engine has stabilized and is ready for release. It is your last chance to report critical regressions before we release the stable version. Now, not even a full week later, we’re ready with our second snapshot. This RC2 fixes the last of the critical regressions that we are aware of. Unless someone reports a new regression coming from the changes made in RC1 or RC2, we should be on track to release 4.5 stable soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point in the process you will see the activity on GitHub slow down as we avoid merging work for 4.5. Our focus in the coming days will be on preparing the release, and queuing up all the changes we would like to merge early in the 4.6 release cycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please consider &lt;a href="#support">supporting the project financially&lt;/a>, if you are able. Godot is maintained by the efforts of volunteers and a small team of paid contributors. Your donations go towards sponsoring their work and ensuring they can dedicate their undivided attention to the needs of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.rc2/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3410180/Overlooting/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Overlooting&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, &lt;em>a dungeon crawler where inventory management is crucial, as you must adapt your strategy to a skill tree that changes every run! You can buy the game on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3410180/Overlooting/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a>, and follow the developers on &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/posingpossums.bsky.social">Bluesky&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between RC 1 and RC 2. This section covers all changes made since the &lt;a href="/article/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-1/">RC 1 snapshot&lt;/a>, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Animation: Move Skeleton3D init process (for dirty flags) into &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">POST_ENTER_TREE&lt;/code> from &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ENTER_TREE&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110145">GH-110145&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buildsystem: Bump version to 4.5-rc (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110285">GH-110285&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buildsystem: Fix Wayland build with OpenGL disabled (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110294">GH-110294&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C#: Fix the issue preventing installing C# binaries on Android devices with api &amp;lt;= 29 (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110260">GH-110260&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C#: Require &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">net9.0&lt;/code> for Android exports (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110263">GH-110263&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Fix Resource duplicate calls &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ImageTexture::set_image&lt;/code> with an invalid image (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110215">GH-110215&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix “SpriteFrames” editor not fully hidding the bottom panel (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110280">GH-110280&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDExtension: Fix &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">WindowUtils::copy_and_rename_pdb&lt;/code> regression (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110033">GH-110033&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Metal: Ensure baked Metal binaries can be loaded on the minimum target OS (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110264">GH-110264&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>10 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>9 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-rc2">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-rc1 snapshot. You can also review &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5">all changes included in 4.5&lt;/a> compared to the previous 4.4 feature release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/2dd26a027a99633231184616d4dd287bbdd1c0a3">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2dd26a027&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-rc2">
Download Godot 4.5 rc2
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-2.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc2/Godot_v4.5-rc2_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-rc2">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the Release Candidate stage, we focus exclusively on solving showstopping regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken, without workaround). You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the RC snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-2/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-2.webp</image></item><item><title>Release candidate: Godot 4.5 RC 1</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-1/</link><summary>Godot 4.5 stable release is imminent; let the last round(s) of testing begin!</summary><description>&lt;p>The final stage of development for Godot 4.5 has arrived: the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle#Release_candidate">Release Candidate&lt;/a>. This means that all of our planned features are in place and the most critical regressions have been tackled, so we’re confident that it’s now ready for production use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, we can never be 100% sure that the release is ready to be published without very extensive testing from the community. So while Godot 4.5 is now ready for testing on existing projects (always make a copy/backup before upgrading, preferably with version control), we’re eager to hear how it fares and whether any new major issues have gone unnoticed until now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we are confident that we are &lt;em>nearly&lt;/em> ready to release. There will be at least one more RC release after this one containing bug fixes for exporting C# projects to certain, older, Android devices and for shipping baked shaders on iOS devices. We have fixes in the queue already and anticipate merging them promptly and releasing an RC2 early next week. If no major regressions are reported with RC1/RC2, we anticipate releasing 4.5 stable shortly after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please consider &lt;a href="#support">supporting the project financially&lt;/a>, if you are able. Godot is maintained by the efforts of volunteers and a small team of paid contributors. Your donations go towards sponsoring their work and ensuring they can dedicate their undivided attention to the needs of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.rc1/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3064030/Whimside/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Whimside&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, &lt;em>a creature collector where your pixel art companions keep you company at the bottom of your screen. You can buy the game on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3064030/Whimside/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a>, and follow the developer on &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/toadzillart.itch.io">Bluesky&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Toadzillart">YouTube&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We covered the most important highlights from Godot 4.5 in the previous &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">&lt;strong>4.5 beta 1 blog post&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, so if you haven’t read that one, have a look to be introduced to the main new features added in the 4.5 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially if you’re testing 4.5 for the first time, you’ll want to get a condensed overview of what new features you might want to make use of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This section covers the most relevant changes made since the &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-7/">beta 7 snapshot&lt;/a>, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Core: Fix regression in mechanism to hold objects while emitting (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109770">GH-109770&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Make &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">SceneTree&lt;/code> not crash when receiving a notification without a root being set (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110041">GH-110041&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Add single-object inspect command backwards compatible API for potential regression (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110043">GH-110043&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix Range scale overflow (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110107">GH-110107&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export: Fix editor export plugins always causing resources to be edited (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110057">GH-110057&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Do not set flags when &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PopupMenu::set_visible&lt;/code> is called to hide popup (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110049">GH-110049&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Input: Fix &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Input.get_joy_info()&lt;/code> regression after the SDL input driver PR (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108214">GH-108214&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Porting: macOS: Process joypad input directly in the embedded process (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109603">GH-109603&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Add GENERAL resource usage to the render graph and fix mutable texture initialization in D3D12 (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110204">GH-110204&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: MSDF: Fix outline bleed out at small sizes (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110148">GH-110148&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we’ve tightened our policy on what kind of changes can be merged leading to the release candidate stage, there aren’t a lot of changes in this snapshot. &lt;strong>18 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>24 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-rc1">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta7 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/6c9aa4c7d3b9b91cd50714c40eeb234874df7075">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">6c9aa4c7d&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-rc1">
Download Godot 4.5 rc1
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-1.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-rc1/Godot_v4.5-rc1_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-rc1">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the Release Candidate stage, we focus exclusively on solving showstopping regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken, without workaround). You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the RC snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-1/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/release-candidate-godot-4-5-rc-1.webp</image></item><item><title>Godot XR update - August 2025</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-xr-update-aug-2025/</link><summary>Upcoming XR game jam, using the XR editor, new release channels and the new Render Models API</summary><description>&lt;h2 id="godot-xr-community-game-jam">Godot XR Community Game Jam&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Starting on 8 September 2025 the Godot XR Community is hosting its &lt;a href="https://itch.io/jam/godot-xr-game-jam-sep-2025">fourth Godot XR game jam&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Participants have a week to put together a small XR game using the Godot Game Engine. In addition, special consideration will be given to participants using the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/godot-game-engine/7713660705416473/">Godot XR editor&lt;/a> to create their entry!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a great way to try out some XR development and hone your game design skills, as well as provide feedback to help improve the XR editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We invite you to take this opportunity to try out Godot as an XR platform! The XR channel on the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/godotengine">official Godot Discord&lt;/a> is a great place to get help.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-a-game-entirely-in-the-xr-editor">Creating a game entirely in the XR editor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And on the topic of using the XR editor to create an XR game, during the Godot Wild Jam in May, David and Logan challenged themselves to create their entry entirely in VR - without using their PCs at all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this devlog video by Logan, they explain how it went:&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" style="width: 100%; height: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9;" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6RE8KuCspqw" title="Can we make a Godot VR Game... in VR?" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Were they successful? Watch to find out!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pre-release-channels-on-horizonos">Pre-release channels on HorizonOS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To improve development and testing of the XR editor, we have set up &lt;strong>DEV&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>BETA&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>RC&lt;/strong> (release candidate) pre-release channels in the Horizon store to provide the community with pre-release builds of the XR editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interested users can self-subscribe to the pre-release channels using the following links:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/3yJ7i8kop">DEV channel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">BETA channel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/6Ls6Bfa34">RC channel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After joining the pre-release channels, users can change the XR editor active channel by visiting the app’s “Settings” page in-headset, or via the “Version” dropdown in the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/godot-game-engine/7713660705416473/">app’s store page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="render-models-support-coming-in-godot-45">Render models support coming in Godot 4.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Render models is a new API added to OpenXR 1.1.49 that provides access to various 3D assets accessible in the runtime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its main focus is to provide accurate render models for the physical controllers the player is using and accurately placing those in the virtual world. These models come with metadata and tracking data that result in full animation of these assets. Thus they react properly to button presses and other interactions the player is performing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107388">implementation in Godot&lt;/a> was made possible thanks to the Godot Integration Project that Khronos is currently funding and allowed Godot to implement this logic early. In doing so, runtime implementations could be tested and this provided feedback that allowed this API to be published.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>SteamVR added support for this API in their 2.12 release.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PICO has added support for this API in their 5.14.0 release, currently supporting PICO 4 Ultra devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other vendors are expected to provide support in the near future.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="995" style="width: 100%; height: 100%; aspect-ratio: 9/16;" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DfOW6tj0Pk4" title="Godot OpenXR Render Models demo" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="">&lt;/iframe></description><category>Progress Report</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-xr-update-aug-2025/</guid><dc:creator>Bastiaan Olij</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/august-2025-update-godot-xr-community.webp</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 7</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-7/</link><summary>Two more for the road!</summary><description>&lt;p>While we initially anticipated our next snapshot to begin release candidate phase, we left open the possibility of another beta pass if any significant blockers persisted. And while the overwhelming majority have since been handled, this extra pass is to ensure debug symbols are supported for Android platforms. While this was always something that could be done when building from source, a long-term goal is official access to debug symbols, making this something we want to get right out of the gate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta7/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2702170/Strange_Jigsaws/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Strange Jigsaws&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, a game of strange jigsaws! You can buy the game on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2702170/Strange_Jigsaws/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a>, and follow the developer on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@FLEBpuzzles">YouTube&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/flebpuzzles.bsky.social">Bluesky&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 6 and beta 7. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 6 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3D: Create an undo/redo action when pinning a SoftBody3D point in the editor (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109828">GH-109828&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audio: Web: Fix &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AudioStreamPlayer.get_playback_position()&lt;/code> returning incorrect values for samples (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109790">GH-109790&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Revert “Prevent crashing if &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">max_threads&lt;/code> is zero.” (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/110003">GH-110003&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Document ClassDB not storing information on user-defined classes (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109747">GH-109747&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Allow extending previously-non-abstract scripts that became abstract (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109903">GH-109903&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Don’t start editor as unsaved (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109825">GH-109825&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Input: Revert “[Web] Disregard touch events in pointer callbacks” (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109936">GH-109936&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Porting: Android: Fix safe area regression on older Android versions (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109818">GH-109818&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Treat missing variants as normal cache misses during shader cache lookup (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109882">GH-109882&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>29 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>47 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta7">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta6 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/4ebf67c12dcdffcb69242569c118a371a654b6ae">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4ebf67c12&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta7">
Download Godot 4.5 beta7
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-7.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta7/Godot_v4.5-beta7_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta7">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-7/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-7.webp</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 6</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-6/</link><summary>One more for the road!</summary><description>&lt;p>It’s been a long journey, but we’re at the tail-end of 4.5’s beta cycle at last; thank you to everyone who contributed during this stage! As such, you can expect this to be our final beta release for 4.5 (probably), with release candidates just around the corner. Should this indeed be our final beta snapshot, all further changes will be &lt;em>strictly&lt;/em> regression fixes; the content available here will be largely reflective of the 4.5 release. As always, users are strongly encouraged to test this snapshot to catch the remaining few release blockers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta6/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2471970/Planetary_Life/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Planetary Life&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, an evolution simulator where you guide custom creations from single-celled organisms to a modern civilization! You can buy the early-access title on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2471970/Planetary_Life/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a>, and follow the developer on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@sotenbox">YouTube&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sotenbox">Twitter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 5 and beta 6. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 5 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rename-svgtexture-to-dpitexture-mark-as-experimental">Rename &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">SVGTexture&lt;/code> to &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DPITexture&lt;/code>, mark as “experimental”&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We generally don’t highlight reversions/renames in these blogposts, but this is a major exception that warrants added context. The original intent of &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">SVGTexture&lt;/code> was to handle icons that respect the font oversampling in the editor. That’s literally it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/storage/blog/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-6/dpi-compare.webp" alt="DPI Compare" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is part of the reason we never gave the feature its own dedicated section, beyond a bullet-point in its introductory blog. However, the reception to what should’ve been a fringe feature was far larger than we intended. Many users, understandably, took the feature to mean full-blown support for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash">Flash-like&lt;/a> graphics and realtime rasterization. The name and description ended up overselling our niche utility as a general-purpose solution; one which it was woefully underequipped to handle. Despite the original author, &lt;a href="https://github.com/bruvzg">bruvzg&lt;/a>, making excellent strides towards refining and expanding functionality, it was ultimately akin to applying a bandage on a broken leg. Turning this implementation into something general purpose would be beyond the scope of &lt;strong>4.6&lt;/strong>, let alone 4.5! The rebranding and experimental designation are our ninth-inning resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature has a limited use-case, and will not be extended beyond that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Having said that&lt;/em>: this is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> us saying “no” to the prospect of realtime support for SVG/rasterized visuals. On the contrary: that’s exactly why we’re making this designation in the first place! The support for this functionality is very obvious, but it needs to be done right. So while that might be out-of-scope for 4.5, it’s not out-of-scope for Godot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109811">GH-109811&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109805">GH-109805&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="and-more">And more!&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Export: Android: Revert the removal of the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gradle_build/compress_native_libraries&lt;/code> export option (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107681">GH-107681&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Autocompletion: Don’t call const functions (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109297">GH-109297&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XR: Add &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CameraServer&lt;/code> &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">feeds_updated&lt;/code> signal, and document async behavior (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108165">GH-108165&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Use MSDF instead of MTSDF for font rendering (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109437">GH-109437&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Input: Add methods to check which event first triggered “just pressed/released” state (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109540">GH-109540&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shaders: Improve shader overloaded function error reporting (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109548">GH-109548&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Update &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_physics_process&lt;/code> and &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_process&lt;/code> docs to reflect implementation (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109320">GH-109320&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix snapping logic in Range (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109100">GH-109100&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Document &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Tree.item_collapsed&lt;/code> also being emitted when the item is expanded (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109242">GH-109242&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Fix material removal clearing all instances of shared texture arrays (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109644">GH-109644&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>55 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>111 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta6">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta5 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/d5ad0556a2c04c50694b5c04dc1b3bf03ecd7113">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">d5ad0556a&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta6">
Download Godot 4.5 beta6
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-6.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta6/Godot_v4.5-beta6_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta6">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-6/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-6.webp</image></item><item><title>Submissions open for Godot 2025 showreel</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/submissions-open-godot-2025-showreel/</link><summary>Showcase your Godot creations in 2025! We're inviting submissions of short videos featuring your published or in-progress Godot games or tools. Don't miss this chance to be a part of it!</summary><description>&lt;p>Showcase your Godot Engine 2025 creations! We invite you to submit videos featuring your published or in-progress games or tools so we can make the Godot 2025 Showreel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our annual showreels are informative and celebratory showcases, to highlight the wide array of projects developed using the Godot Engine. If you want to participate this year and share your Godot-made game, app, or tool, submit your entry starting today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new-this-year">What’s new this year?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This year, we want to invite more people to participate in the voting phase. So, if you are a member of the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Development Fund&lt;/a>, you will be able to cast your votes alongside the Godot maintainers! To be eligible to vote, you need to have a recurrent donation active.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-submit">How to submit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can submit your entry in our &lt;a href="https://showreel.godotengine.org/">Godot Showreel website&lt;/a>. Before submitting, please read the &lt;a href="https://showreel.godotengine.org/about">submission guidelines&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>📅 &lt;strong>Submissions close on October 1st 2025&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>📅 &lt;strong>Voting starts on October 6th 2025&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="need-inspiration">Need inspiration?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Check out our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n1Lon_Q2T18&amp;amp;list=PLeG_dAglpVo6EpaO9A1nkwJZOwrfiLdQ8&amp;amp;index=1">showreel playlist&lt;/a> for some creative sparks and see what makes a great submission! Here is last year’s showreel:&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n1Lon_Q2T18" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" style="width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16 / 9; height: auto;">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Good luck! We can’t wait to see your creations!&lt;/p></description><category>News</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/submissions-open-godot-2025-showreel/</guid><dc:creator>Emi</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/godot-showreel-2023.webp</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 5</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-5/</link><summary>Back to our regularly scheduled schedule!</summary><description>&lt;p>The weekly pace of beta snapshots returns with a bang! While the overall number of changes might be smaller, that’s simply a logical consequence of a much tighter scope on what can be integrated at this stage, with even generic bugfixes given a higher scrutiny. Regression fixes are our number one priority as we grow closer to the end of the beta period, and our contributors have been putting in the work to make that happen; shoutouts to everyone who’s lent a hand!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta5/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3385370/Maze_Mice/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Maze Mice&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, a bullet heaven roguelite where time only moves when you move! You can buy the game on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3385370/Maze_Mice/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://trampolinetales.itch.io/maze-mice">itch.io&lt;/a>, and follow the developers on &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/TrampolineTales.com">Bluesky&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 4 and beta 5. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 4 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2D: Rename Camera2D &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">set_position_smoothing_enabled&lt;/code> parameter (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109147">GH-109147&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3D: Fix missing 3D gizmos (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109029">GH-109029&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audio: Fix &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AudioListener3D&lt;/code> not tracking velocity for doppler (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108051">GH-108051&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C#: Fix &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Quaternion(Vector3, Vector3)&lt;/code> constructor when vectors are the same (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109281">GH-109281&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Ensure that threads only process one pump task (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108697">GH-108697&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Fix translation remaps incorrectly falling back (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/103838">GH-103838&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Add search keywords for CheckButton and ButtonGroup (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109089">GH-109089&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix inconsistent thumbnail width (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109199">GH-109199&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Deactivate orientation gizmo on window exit (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108374">GH-108374&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Fix ColorPicker linear mode sliders color (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108328">GH-108328&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I18n: Disable auto translation of flag names in the inspector (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109294">GH-109294&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Import: Prevent generating Editor 3D scene preview in headless mode (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109116">GH-109116&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Input: Fix the usage of udev and dbus with SDL joystick input driver (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108373">GH-108373&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigation: Fix path post-processing edgecentered (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109196">GH-109196&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Physics: Revert “SoftBody3D: Support physics Interpolation” (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109265">GH-109265&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: D3D12: Fix shader model check, initialization error handling (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108919">GH-108919&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: OpenGL: Fix crash at startup with “Thread Model” set to “Separate” (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/109057">GH-109057&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thirdparty: Update access-kit to 0.17.0 (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108924">GH-108924&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>43 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>66 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta5">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta4 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/c81fd6c51233a727da528cf7f74137d56b5d6efe">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">c81fd6c51&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta5">
Download Godot 4.5 beta5
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-5.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta5/Godot_v4.5-beta5_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta5">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-5/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-5.webp</image></item><item><title>Godot Foundation welcomes JetBrains as Platinum Sponsor</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/jetbrains-joins-dev-fund-supports-godot/</link><summary>The Godot Foundation is thrilled to welcome JetBrains as a Platinum Sponsor! We’re very grateful for the support, and hope you’ll give them a warm welcome too.</summary><description>&lt;p>We would like to welcome JetBrains as a Platinum Sponsor of the Godot Foundation. The support from JetBrains means a lot to us, so we would love to thank them for enabling us to keep improving the engine for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re not already familiar with JetBrains, they build great developer tools, with some very helpful game development-facing features. JetBrains Rider is a must-have IDE and code editor for GDScript, C#, and C++, with specific support for various different game engines, including Godot. As well as rich editing and &lt;kbd>Ctrl + Click&lt;/kbd> navigation, there are smart features like Find Usages, Rename (no more find/replace!) and specific inspections and quick fixes to help with best practices while writing, debugging or testing code for your game. Check out &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/lp/rider-godot/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rider&amp;amp;utm_content=godot-page-blog">their page for more details&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="free-for-non-commercial-use">Free for non-commercial use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While JetBrains Rider is known as a professional tool, it recently became available for free for non-commercial use. That means if you’re just getting started with Godot, then it’s free for learning. It’s also free for open source, so you can use it to contribute to the engine, and it’s free for content creation, so you can make cool videos of your learning journey too. Other options for &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/rider/buy/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rider&amp;amp;utm_content=godot-licensing&amp;amp;section=commercial&amp;amp;billing=yearly">licensing&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/store/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rider&amp;amp;utm_content=godot-post-discounts&amp;amp;section=discounts&amp;amp;billing=yearly">discounts&lt;/a> are also available.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-message-from-jetbrains">A message from JetBrains:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At JetBrains, we value the diversity of thought and experience in the software industry, such as the many different programming languages and related ecosystems. We can see that there is ample scope for multiple game engines, especially so for a not-for-profit, open-source game engine. Development happens thanks to the dedication of contributors and paid volunteers, and we welcome the chance to support passionate people making a difference with a successful community project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’d like to encourage you to visit the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by the &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>, or to check &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/donate">out the alternative ways to donate&lt;/a>, and join us in supporting such a fantastic project.&lt;/p></description><category>News</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/jetbrains-joins-dev-fund-supports-godot/</guid><dc:creator>Godot Foundation</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/godot-jetbrains.webp</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 4</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-4/</link><summary>More critical fixes coming your way!</summary><description>&lt;p>It’s been a while since our last snapshot, as our team has been quite busy knocking out some critical release-blocker and immediate-blocker issues. Thankfully, we’re back at the point where we can comfortably deliver our latest 4.5 pre-release candidate. As a refresher: the beta period means that the project has entered feature freeze, so the only changes you’ll be seeing are bugfixes and addressing regressions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also try the &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta4/">&lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://www.meta.com/s/h9JcJGHfg">&lt;strong>XR editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, or the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.godotengine.editor.v4">&lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3775050/DOGWALK/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>DOGWALK&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, a title we had the pleasure of showcasing in a &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godot-showcase-dogwalk/">dedicated article&lt;/a>. You can download the game for free on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3775050/DOGWALK/?curator_clanid=41324400">Steam&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blenderstudio.itch.io/dogwalk">itch.io&lt;/a>, and the &lt;a href="https://studio.blender.org/projects/dogwalk/">Blender Studio website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 3 and beta 4. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 3 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Animation: Remove PropertyTweener start warning (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108410">GH-108410&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buildsystem: Android: Update the maven publishing configuration following the deprecation of the OSSHR service (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108393">GH-108393&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buildsystem: Web: Fix Emscripten for WebXR and update minimum version (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107460">GH-107460&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C#: Fix thread deadlock when using a worker thread to load a script with a generic base class (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/99798">GH-99798&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix main editor title after changing language (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108396">GH-108396&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Fix ScriptEditor inline colors float handling (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107904">GH-107904&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Fix autocompletion issues with nested types (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/94996">GH-94996&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Fix lookup symbol for &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">super()&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108306">GH-108306&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Code Editor: Fix “Pick Color” menu option replacing multiple color items (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108431">GH-108431&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: RTL: Add method to get visible content bounding box (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108466">GH-108466&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: RTL: Add option to scroll follow visible characters (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108399">GH-108399&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: TextEdit: Draw guidelines under the text and caret (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108599">GH-108599&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Multiplayer: Fix node cache errors on nested MultiplayerSpawners (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/101416">GH-101416&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Porting: Windows: Add SSE4.2 support runtime check (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108561">GH-108561&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Always perform color correction and debanding on nonlinear sRGB values (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107782">GH-107782&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Fix crash when creating voxel GI data (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108397">GH-108397&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Fix underculling of occulusion culling (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108347">GH-108347&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>79 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>168 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta4">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta3 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/2d113cc224cb9be07866d003819fcef2226a52ea">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2d113cc22&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta4">
Download Godot 4.5 beta4
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-4.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta4/Godot_v4.5-beta4_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta4">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-4/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-4.webp</image></item><item><title>Godot OpenXR Vendors Plugin v4</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-openxr-vendors-plugin-400/</link><summary>What's new in the latest release of the Godot OpenXR Vendors plugin?</summary><description>&lt;p>OpenXR support has been built into Godot since the release of Godot 4.0. However, the &lt;a href="https://github.com/GodotVR/godot_openxr_vendors">OpenXR Vendors plugin&lt;/a> (maintained by Godot’s XR team) includes extensions to OpenXR created by hardware vendors (e.g. Meta, Pico, HTC, etc.), which we’ve chosen to keep outside of Godot itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are happy to announce a new major release of the OpenXR Vendors plugin, which includes some exciting new features!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="version-400">Version 4.0.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://github.com/GodotVR/godot_openxr_vendors/releases/tag/4.0.0-stable">4.0.0 version&lt;/a> was actually released right before GodotCon Boston, but with all the excitement around the event (including our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godotcon-2025-xr-android-recap/">GodotCon presentation&lt;/a>), we never managed to find a time to properly announce it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s some of the key features in the transition from v3 to v4!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="switch-to-khronos-loader">Switch to Khronos loader&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aside from OpenXR vendor extensions, the plugin has historically also included vendor-specific OpenXR loaders for Android. While OpenXR now has a standard loader for Android (which we call “the Khronos loader”), this wasn’t the case when standalone Android headsets first hit the market, and so a number of vendors created their own proprietary loaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, starting with version 4.0.0, we are only including the Khronos loader, which is supported on all the Android headsets supported by the plugin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a step towards eventually including support for the Khronos loader in Godot itself, which will make it possible to export to Android without requiring the plugin at all! That is something that Bastiaan Olij has &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/106891">started working on&lt;/a>, and we hope to merge for Godot 4.6.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dynamic-resolution">Dynamic Resolution&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While hitting your FPS target is important for flat screen games, it’s &lt;em>critically&lt;/em> important in VR and AR, where drops in frame rate can cause discomfort or nausea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Version 4.0.0 adds support for Meta’s Dynamic Resolution feature, which will dynamically scale down the render resolution in response to system load. So, rather than getting lower FPS, the graphics will look somewhat pixelated until system load improves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Side-by-side screenshot of normal resolution and dynamic resolution when load is high" src="/storage/blog/godot-openxr-vendors-400/meta-xr-dynamic-resolution.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature is enabled by default, and so requires no setup to use — just download the new version of the plugin!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://godotvr.github.io/godot_openxr_vendors/manual/meta/dynamic_resolution.html">the documentation&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hybrid-apps">Hybrid Apps&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hybrid Apps are applications that can dynamically switch between fully immersive and floating 2D panels. The Godot &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godot-editor-horizon-store-early-access-release/">XR editor&lt;/a> is itself a Hybrid App.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting with version 4.0.0, developers can make their own Hybrid Apps for Meta headsets! Support for other vendors is in the works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See this &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godotcon-2025-xr-android-recap/">earlier blog&lt;/a> post where we discussed this feature in more detail, and &lt;a href="https://godotvr.github.io/godot_openxr_vendors/manual/hybrid_apps.html">the documentation&lt;/a> on creating your own Hybrid App.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="only-enable-requested-extensions">Only enable requested extensions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In previous versions of the plugin, we’d enable any OpenXR extensions that the plugin supported, if they were available on the headset. This may have been OK when we only supported a handful of extensions, but that number has really started to balloon, and some extensions may have unwanted side effects, including a potential impact on performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why in version 4.0.0 and beyond, there are now project settings to enable or disable any of the OpenXR extensions supported by this plugin, so you can enable only the features that your application needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Project settings dialog with the OpenXR extensions added by this plugin" src="/storage/blog/godot-openxr-vendors-400/godot-openxr-vendors-extension-settings.webp" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="version-410">Version 4.1.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nothing ever stands still in the world of Godot!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We just released &lt;a href="https://github.com/GodotVR/godot_openxr_vendors/releases/tag/4.1.1-stable">version 4.1.1&lt;/a> which includes even more exciting features.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="full-body-tracking">Full Body Tracking&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We’ve supported Meta’s original OpenXR body tracking extension since version 3.0.0, but it only addresses the player’s upper body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this release, we’ve added support for Meta’s full body tracking extension, which includes tracking data for the player’s legs, as well as support for the height calibration extension, and fidelity extension, which allows controlling the tracking data’s level of detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;video autoplay="" loop="" muted="" playsinline="">
&lt;source src="/storage/releases/4.3/video/body-face-tracking.webm" type="video/webm" />
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="application-spacewarp">Application SpaceWarp&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Meta’s Application SpaceWarp is a technology that allows your game to render at half framerate (for example, 36 FPS) and the OpenXR runtime will generate an in-between frames, so that the user will experience full framerate (72 FPS, in this example). This has been shown to increase an application’s frame budget by about ~70%, which can allow rendering higher fidelity graphics than would otherwise be possible on standalone VR hardware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This technology helped deliver AAA graphics in &lt;strong>Assassin’s Creed Nexus VR&lt;/strong>, and now VR games built with Godot can use it too!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The SpaceWarp extension is supported on headsets from Meta and Pico, and with the recent release of the multi-vendor &lt;a href="https://registry.khronos.org/OpenXR/specs/1.1/html/xrspec.html#XR_EXT_frame_synthesis">Frame Synthesis extension&lt;/a>, it’s expected to be supported on headsets from more vendors in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://godotvr.github.io/godot_openxr_vendors/manual/meta/application_space_warp.html">the documentation&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="only-godot-45-and-the-vulkan-mobile-renderer">Only Godot 4.5+ and the Vulkan Mobile renderer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While version 4.1.0 of the OpenXR Vendors Plugin is compatible with both Godot 4.4 and the forthcoming 4.5, Application SpaceWarp will only work when used with Godot 4.5 or later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, this currently only works with the Vulkan Mobile renderer, but there is an &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/97151">open PR&lt;/a> to add support for Godot’s Compatibility renderer (OpenGL) as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="environment-depth">Environment Depth&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In an Augmented Reality (AR) or Mixed Reality (MR) application, by default, all virtual objects rendered by Godot will appear on top of any real world objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meta’s Environment Depth extension provides a realtime depth map of the world in front of the player, which can be used to allow real world objects to occlude — that is, to appear on top of — virtual objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;video autoplay="" loop="" muted="" playsinline="">
&lt;source src="/storage/blog/godot-openxr-vendors-400/meta-xr-environment-depth.webm" type="video/webm" />
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Similar to Application SpaceWarp, this feature will only work when used with Godot 4.5 or later.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="and-more">And more!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are numerous other smaller changes, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Smaller build size!&lt;/strong> The overall package (which includes all platforms) is now 23.3 MB, whereas the last v3 release was 194 MB. That’s almost a 10x improvement!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">XR_FB_composition_layer_image_layout&lt;/code> extension,&lt;/strong> which is useful with OpenXRCompositionLayers using Android surfaces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">XR_FB_composition_layer_depth_test&lt;/code> extension&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">XR_FB_android_surface_swapchain_create&lt;/code> extension&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">XR_META_boundary_visibility&lt;/code> extension&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for the &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">XR_FB_color_space&lt;/code> extension&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add HorizonOS camera permissions when Android CAMERA permission is enabled&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Instant splash screen configuration for Meta headsets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Several bug fixes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And there will be more exciting features to come in the future 🙂&lt;/p></description><category>Progress Report</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-openxr-vendors-plugin-400/</guid><dc:creator>David Snopek</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/godot-openxr-vendors-plugin-400.webp</image></item><item><title>Godot Showcase - Dogwalk</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-showcase-dogwalk/</link><summary>Julien and Simon from Blender Studio tell us about their experience working on Dogwalk.</summary><description>&lt;style>
.julien {
color: #aa77e2;
}
.simon {
color: #40b99f;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;p>Today we want to showcase a very special project. Most of you already know about it since it is really hard to go around any Godot space without finding people excited about Dogwalk. So if somehow you didn’t know about the project or you still haven’t been captivated by their &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c4zP1sUgt6I&amp;amp;list=PLav47HAVZMjkxzzLDqYpTCosbsWjosUN0">video blogs&lt;/a> over at YouTube, you are in for a treat! &lt;strong class="julien">Julien Kaspar&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong class="simon">Simon Thommes&lt;/strong> from the &lt;a href="https://studio.blender.org">Blender Studio&lt;/a> team tell us about their experience developing their first Godot game: Dogwalk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The game is already out on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3775050/DOGWALK/">Steam&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blenderstudio.itch.io/dogwalk">Itch.io&lt;/a>, and you can also get the project files with tons of extras from &lt;a href="https://studio.blender.org/projects/dogwalk/">their website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gPENs56vfYk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" style="width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16 / 9; height: auto;">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;h2 id="can-you-tell-us-a-little-bit-about-your-project">Can you tell us a little bit about your project?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="julien">Julien:&lt;/strong>
For this year the Blender Studio, which is the in-house art department of the Blender project, decided to focus on smaller short-term projects. We aimed for four months for each of them so I saw the unique chance to pitch a tiny game project. And the scope really had to be tiny to be able to pull off a game for the first time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogwalk is a short, wholesome interactive story about a dog and a kid decorating a snowman together. One big focus was on wordless storytelling through reactive gameplay.
It’s not strictly about fun or overcoming challenges. It’s about allowing the player to shape and experience the relationship between the two characters, simply by constraining the player to a small set of mechanics and have the game react to what they do with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/showcase/dogwalk/dogwalk-1.jpg" alt="" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-did-you-pick-godot-to-develop-this-project">Why did you pick Godot to develop this project?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="julien">Julien:&lt;/strong>
One of our primary missions (and constraints) is that we demonstrate how people can make entire movies by only using free open-source software. We call these “Open Projects” since we also licence them as open source and make the sources available.
So for a game project it seemed natural to use Godot for it. Personally I’m a fan of the engine and project, and was quite excited to be able to use it for a professional project in a team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every one of our projects also comes with some Blender-specific development targets. In this case we took a closer look at the export and import of glTF animations and assets. We created a pipeline for ourselves to stress-test the interoperability between Blender and Godot as much as our production scope allowed us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/showcase/dogwalk/dogwalk-7.jpg" alt="" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-did-the-project-compare-with-your-past-experiences-as-a-studio-who-usually-does-animation-movies-rather-than-games">How did the project compare with your past experiences as a studio who usually does animation movies rather than games?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="julien">Julien:&lt;/strong>
Pretty different. One big change is the shift from storyboarding/editorial to game prototyping/playtesting. In our film productions the story artists and animators would typically helm the project, but in this case I was doing it with an emphasis on development and design. It put us in very different shoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The animation and rigging workflow is also very different. Animators don’t have the usual fine level of control and instead need to playtest the game to see the animations applied in action. We were also not used to rigging for export and game engines in mind, so we made some mistakes on that side that needed creative problem solving later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the biggest hurdle was to have the entire art team use Git LFS for version control. That was … quite a journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-did-you-find-the-current-export-pipeline-from-blender-to-godot">How did you find the current export pipeline from Blender to Godot?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="simon">Simon:&lt;/strong>
We were quite impressed immediately with how seamless the base level compatibility was. As an initial test we had built a demo environment in Blender and exported it as one big glTF to throw it in Godot. Everything just worked. That’s definitely nothing to scoff at.
Of course, we had a more refined pipeline setup in mind that would allow us to collaborate and iterate on assets and sets from within Blender.
But the extensible ecosystem of Godot and using glTF made it possible for us to hook up anywhere in the process and inject our own functionality. Coming in from outside, I was really quite surprised how powerful our available options are without a core understanding of how the engine works.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="were-there-any-quirks-with-the-way-the-material-rendering-and-animations-were-converted-from-blender-to-godot">Were there any quirks with the way the material rendering and animations were converted from Blender to Godot?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="simon">Simon:&lt;/strong>
We actually ran into a couple of issues with our stop motion animation style, which apparently seems to not be very common for game animation. So both on the export and the import level there were some parts that made assumptions over keyframe interpolation causing some obscure issues that took quite some investigation. But now those are all resolved.
Since Godot was always our target for rendering, there were some shader features that we didn’t replicate for the preview that we had in Blender. That’s mainly the fake paper thickness, for which we had two separate effects. But since the effects are so subtle, it wasn’t really required for the asset creation process.
We’re also not used to having to make drastic cuts due to performance, coming from usually doing offline rendering. So there were some rendering features that we had to disable and replace with some clever lighting cheats to save the frames.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/showcase/dogwalk/dogwalk-8.jpg" alt="" />&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="are-there-suggestions-for-improvement-in-this-context">Are there suggestions for improvement in this context?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="simon">Simon:&lt;/strong>
Most of the things we ran into, we reported right away and they have already been fixed. It’s been great to see how actively the Godot community has been responding to the issues we found.
There have been some other more big-picture issues that we ran into when collaborating as a team and using versioning. This mainly relates to UIDs and caching going out of sync.
Since these issues are usually complex and relate to our pipeline and people’s individual systems, these were a bit more tricky to identify and report. Especially with the additional burden of our art team using git for the first time, it wasn’t always clear what were issues that were actually caused by Godot.
I really hope that we can find the time to sit together with some Blender and Godot developers to see what we can collectively take away from these issues and potentially change to make sure collaborating as a team using Blender and Godot is a smooth process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="while-making-your-game-were-there-any-features-that-were-sorely-missing-in-blender-or-in-godot">While making your game, were there any features that were sorely missing in Blender or in Godot?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong class="julien">Julien:&lt;/strong>
Nothing that couldn’t be added manually or fixed with workarounds.
With one of the main gameplay and visual elements being the leash, sadly there was no Line3D node. But luckily the community had a &lt;a href="https://github.com/CozyCubeGames/godot-lines-and-trails-3d">handy plugin&lt;/a> to immediately fill in that gap.
We also ran into some limitations with our animation system, but that &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/102398#issuecomment-2949711987">will be fixed in the upcoming 4.5 release&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/showcase/dogwalk/dogwalk-4.jpg" alt="" />&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>Thank you very much Julien and Simon for taking the time to answer our questions, and we look forward to see what you do next with Godot!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play Dogwalk, it is free and already out on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3775050/DOGWALK/">Steam&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://blenderstudio.itch.io/dogwalk">Itch.io&lt;/a>. Make sure to get the supporter DLC on Steam, donate via Itch, or subscribe to Blender Studio if you are interested in seeing more projects like this in the future.&lt;/p></description><category>Showcase</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/godot-showcase-dogwalk/</guid><dc:creator>Emi</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/assets/showcase/dogwalk/thumbnail.jpeg</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 3</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-3/</link><summary>Gotta go fast!</summary><description>&lt;p>The previous &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-2/">beta snapshot&lt;/a> was one week ago, and you mean to tell me another one is here already? Indeed, the community has done a terrific job of reporting regressions and getting fixes integrated in record time! That release was also responsible for the last of the merge exceptions being integrated, so everything from this point forward will be strictly addressing regressions and bugfixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta3/">try the &lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> or the &lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2945950/Dice_n_Goblins/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Dice ‘n Goblins&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, &lt;em>a dungeon-crawling, turn-based RPG where the fate of your goblin in a seemingly endless labyrinth is guided by the roll of the die! You can buy the game &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2945950/Dice_n_Goblins/?curator_clanid=41324400">on Steam&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 2 and beta 3. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 2 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2D: Fix smoothed camera position with limits (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108200">GH-108200&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Animation: Fix animation keying not working with toggleable inspector sections (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107919">GH-107919&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audio: Fix audio name doesn’t appear in exports of child classes of &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AudioStream&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107598">GH-107598&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C#: Fix crash in C# bindings generator with bad enum documentation XML (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108262">GH-108262&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core: Fix typed collections using same reference across scene instances (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108216">GH-108216&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export: Update DotNet iOS export process (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/100187">GH-100187&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Autocompletion: Fix type resolution when assigning &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Variant&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/92584">GH-92584&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Fix crash when using a modulo operator between a float and an integer (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/101536">GH-101536&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Improve GDScript editor support for global enums (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/102186">GH-102186&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: LSP: Don’t poll during editor setup (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108140">GH-108140&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Particles: Fix floating point precision errors when setting particle trail length (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107568">GH-107568&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Particles: Fix particles resetting properties when emitting is toggled (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107915">GH-107915&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Physics: Jolt: wake up a soft body when its transform changes (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108094">GH-108094&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: FTI: Add reset on setting &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">top_level&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108112">GH-108112&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Metal: Use image atomic operations on supported Apple hardware (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/108028">GH-108028&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>37 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>56 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta3">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta2 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/4d1f26e1fd1fa46f2223fe0b6ac300744bf79b88">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4d1f26e1f&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta3">
Download Godot 4.5 beta3
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-3.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta3/Godot_v4.5-beta3_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta3">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Android Library infrastructure we’ve been using &lt;a href="https://central.sonatype.org/news/20250326_ossrh_sunset/">has been sunset&lt;/a>, so those components are currently unavailable.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-3/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-3.webp</image></item><item><title>Dev snapshot: Godot 4.5 beta 2</title><link>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-2/</link><summary>The cow goes "moo"! The duck goes "quack"! The bug goes *squash*!</summary><description>&lt;p>It’s been two weeks since the release of &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, and already a plethora of various bugs and regressions have been dealt with, so it’s time for 4.5 beta 2. This is an ongoing process of course, so there’s going to be a couple more beta snapshots following this, but progress has been smooth and we’re quite satisfied with our current timeframe; great work, everyone!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#downloads">Jump to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> section&lt;/a>, and give it a spin right now, or continue reading to learn more about improvements in this release. You can also &lt;a href="https://editor.godotengine.org/releases/4.5.beta2/">try the &lt;strong>Web editor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> or the &lt;strong>Android editor&lt;/strong> for this release. If you are interested in the latter, please request to join &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/godot-testers">our testing group&lt;/a> to get access to pre-release builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr />
&lt;p>&lt;em>The cover illustration is from&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1948490/Xion_Leak/?curator_clanid=41324400">&lt;strong>Xion Leak&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, &lt;em>a fast-paced, co-op platformer where you win trophies by evading the dangers of the mysterious Foreman! You can buy the game &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1948490/Xion_Leak/?curator_clanid=41324400">on Steam&lt;/a>, and follow the developers &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/gentlebeastsstudio.bsky.social">on Bluesky&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an overview of what’s new overall in Godot 4.5, have a look at the highlights for &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/">4.5 beta 1&lt;/a>, which cover a lot of the changes. This blog post only covers the changes between beta 1 and beta 2. This section covers the most relevant changes made since the beta 1 snapshot, which are largely regression fixes:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="input-sdl3-joystick-input-driver">Input: SDL3 joystick input driver&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Even though we’re now in feature freeze, you might recall us mentioning a handful of pre-approved exceptions. This was by far the biggest one of note: &lt;strong>SDL3 input&lt;/strong>! For those unaware: &lt;abbr title="Simple DirectMedia Layer">SDL&lt;/abbr> is a collection of common APIs shared across an ever-growing portion of software, allowing for convenient and easy integration of common tasks and actions for developers. They’ve recently came out with their 3.0 release &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/120491416">this January&lt;/a>, bringing with it a multitude of features and enhancements alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First-time contributor &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nintorch">Nintorch&lt;/a> took to the integration of one such feature: their input handler (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/106218">GH-106218&lt;/a>). This implementation was so thorough, that it entirely &lt;em>replaced&lt;/em> our old input method! The more technical nuances of this change are better delved into on the PR itself, but the biggest takeaway is that this opens the door for easy and native integration of additional input features; while we won’t be seeing any of these in 4.5, Nintorch already has a &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107967">work-in-progress PR&lt;/a> that’s set to add these features.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="changes-from-beta-1">Changes from Beta 1&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While it’s not uncommon for features we’ve previously highlighted to get new changes/adjustments, it’s rare for follow-up posts to actually highlight them. This is due to the majority of cases being a “finalization” of the feature in question, or otherwise making everything work as expected once the community unearths new bugs. However, there were a couple of features that warrant a special mention here, as a follow-up to them was explicitly highlighted in beta 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is regarding the &lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/#gdscript">new &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">abstract&lt;/code> keyword in GDScript&lt;/a>. Prior to the publication of that blogpost, it was decided by the GDScript team that the keyword shall be converted to an annotation instead. In practice, this is a simple adjustment to existing implementations: just prepend an &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">@&lt;/code>!&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre class="highlight">&lt;code># Before:
abstract class_name MyBaseClass
# After:
@abstract class_name MyBaseClass
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Next, we’ve made the tough decision to revert the &lt;a href="/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-1/#editor">scene preview thumbnails&lt;/a>. We are very aware of how much people want this feature; trust us, we want them just as badly! But the ramifications of this change proved to be far greater than anticipated, and ultimately doesn’t suit the beta stage of production. We shall revisit this PR early in the 4.6 development cycle, where such a change has the chance to breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="and-more">And more!&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3D: Fix freelook in 3D when multiple viewports are open (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107530">GH-107530&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audio: iOS: Add permission request for Apple embedded platforms, fix microphone input (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107973">GH-107973&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audio: Web: Fix Webkit leak caused by the position reporting audio worklets (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107948">GH-107948&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buildsystem: Enable &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">lightmapper&lt;/code> and &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">xatlas_unwrap&lt;/code> modules on Android and iOS editors (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107635">GH-107635&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editor: Allow toggling UID display in path properties (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/106716">GH-106716&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export: Android: Implement sparse bundle PCK support (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/105984">GH-105984&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: Fix errors not being emitted when debugger breaks on script errors (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107663">GH-107663&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GDScript: LSP: Fix file URI handling + warn about workspace project mismatch (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/104401">GH-104401&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Android: Address API 35 UI behavior changes (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107742">GH-107742&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI: Fix and improve editor state persistence for the VisualShader editor (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/98566">GH-98566&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Allow double precision modelview (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/106951">GH-106951&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Fix baked VoxelGI using the wrong color space (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107776">GH-107776&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rendering: Fix GLES3 stereo output (sRGB + lens distortion) (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107698">GH-107698&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XR: Add support for running hybrid apps from the XR editor (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/103972">GH-103972&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XR: OpenXR: Add support for render models extension (&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/pull/107388">GH-107388&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="changelog">Changelog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>82 contributors&lt;/strong> submitted &lt;strong>152 fixes&lt;/strong> for this release. See our &lt;a href="https://godotengine.github.io/godot-interactive-changelog/#4.5-beta2">&lt;strong>interactive changelog&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for the complete list of changes since the previous 4.5-beta2 snapshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is built from commit &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/commit/e1b4101e3460dd9c6ba0b7f8d88e9751b8383f5b">&lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">e1b4101e3&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloads">Downloads&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="card card-download">
&lt;a class="card-download-link" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta2">
Download Godot 4.5 beta2
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="card-download-details">
&lt;img class="lightbox-ignore" src="/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-2.webp" />
&lt;div class="card-download-platforms">
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-linux">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/linux.svg" title="Linux" alt="Linux" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Linux
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_linux.x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_mono_linux_x86_64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-linux">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-macos">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/macos.svg" title="macOS" alt="macOS" class="lightbox-ignore" />
macOS
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_mono_macos.universal.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-macos">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="download-platform platform-windows">
&lt;img width="24" height="24" src="/assets/images/platforms/windows.svg" title="Windows" alt="Windows" class="lightbox-ignore" />
Windows
&lt;/div>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_win64.exe.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
Standard
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot-builds/releases/download/4.5-beta2/Godot_v4.5-beta2_mono_win64.zip" class="btn btn-download btn-download-primary btn-download-primary--mono platform-windows">
&lt;div class="download-title">
.NET
&lt;/div>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-download-sublinks">
&lt;a class="card-download-other" href="/download/archive/4.5-beta2">
Export templates and other downloads
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="card-download-donate" href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;style>
.thankyou-wrapper {
position: fixed;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
background: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.85);
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
z-index: 10;
}
.thankyou {
background: var(--base-color);
box-shadow: var(--more-shadow);
padding: 30px;
display: flex;
flex-direction: column;
align-items: center;
text-align: center;
position: relative;
border-radius: 13px;
}
.thankyou-reading {
font-size: 16px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
font-size: 16px;
margin: 0;
margin-left: 48px;
padding-left: 0;
}
.thankyou-donate {
margin-bottom: 24px;
text-align: center;
}
.btn.btn-donate {
background-color: var(--primary-color);
color: hsla(0, 0%, 100%, 0.9);
font-size: 22px;
font-weight: 600;
margin-bottom: 26px;
}
.thankyou h2 {
text-shadow: var(--base-shadow);
font-size: 36px;
font-weight: 800;
margin-bottom: 12px;
}
.thankyou h2 .anchored-link {
/* Hiding the anchored text automatically added on blogposts */
display: none !important;
}
.thankyou p {
max-width: 620px;
font-size: 25px;
}
@media (max-width: 768px) {
.thankyou-wrapper {
display: block;
}
.thankyou {
position: absolute;
top: 0;
left: 0;
right: 0;
bottom: 0;
overflow: scroll;
padding: 30px 40px 18px 40px;
}
.thankyou-reading-list {
margin-left: 24px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
width: 48px;
height: 48px;
display: flex;
justify-content: center;
align-items: center;
}
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup {
cursor: pointer;
position: absolute;
top: 12px;
right: 12px;
}
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
background: transparent !important; /* for overwriting the style in the blogposts img */
}
@media (prefers-color-scheme: light) {
.btn-close-thankyou-popup img {
filter: invert(1);
opacity: 0.75;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;script>
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
const thankYouWrapper = document.getElementById('thank-you');
// Close itself, when clicked outside of the popup area.
thankYouWrapper.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
if (e.target === thankYouWrapper) {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
// Close with a close button.
const thankYouBackButton = document.querySelector('.btn-close-thankyou-popup');
thankYouBackButton.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
});
// Open from the main download buttons.
const downloadButtons = document.querySelectorAll('.btn-download, .download-button');
downloadButtons.forEach((it) => {
if (it.dataset?.external === "yes") {
return;
}
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
document.querySelector('.btn.btn-donate').focus();
});
});
// Open from the all downloads list.
const downloadLinks = document.querySelectorAll('.download-link');
downloadLinks.forEach((it) => {
it.addEventListener('click', () => {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = '';
});
});
// Close the dialog when the user presses the escape key.
document.addEventListener('keydown', (e) => {
if (e.key === 'Escape') {
thankYouWrapper.style.display = 'none';
}
});
});
&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="thankyou-wrapper" id="thank-you" style="display: none;">
&lt;div class="thankyou">
&lt;h2>Godot is downloading...&lt;/h2>
&lt;p class="thankyou-donate">
Godot exists thanks to donations from people like you. Help us continue our work:
&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org" class="btn btn-donate">
Make a Donation
&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="btn-close-thankyou-popup">
&lt;img src="/assets/icons/cross.svg" width="24" height="24" alt="Close this popup" class="lightbox-ignore" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Standard build&lt;/strong> includes support for GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>.NET build&lt;/strong> (marked as &lt;code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mono&lt;/code>) includes support for C#, as well as GDScript and GDExtension.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="card card-warning">
&lt;p>
While engine maintainers try their best to ensure that each preview snapshot and release candidate is stable, this is by definition &lt;strong>a pre-release piece of software&lt;/strong>. Be sure to make frequent backups, or use a version control system such as Git, to preserve your projects in case of corruption or data loss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During the beta stage, we focus on solving both regressions (i.e. something that worked in a previous release is now broken) and significant new bugs introduced by new features. You can have a look at our current &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/godotengine/projects/61">list of regressions and significant issues&lt;/a> which we aim to address before releasing 4.5. This list is dynamic and will be updated if we discover new showstopping issues after more users start testing the beta snapshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every release, we accept that there are going to be various issues which have already been reported but haven’t been fixed yet. See the GitHub issue tracker for a complete list of &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug">known bugs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are currently no known issues introduced by this release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bug-reports">Bug reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a tester, we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">open bug reports&lt;/a> if you experience issues with this release. Please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/issues">existing issues on GitHub&lt;/a> first, using the search function with relevant keywords, to ensure that the bug you experience is not already known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, any change that would cause a regression in your projects is very important to report (e.g. if something that worked fine in previous 4.x releases, but no longer works in this snapshot).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Godot is a non-profit, open source game engine developed by hundreds of contributors on their free time, as well as a handful of part or full-time developers hired thanks to &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">generous donations from the Godot community&lt;/a>. A big thank you to everyone who has contributed &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/AUTHORS.md">their time&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/godotengine/godot/blob/master/DONORS.md">their financial support&lt;/a> to the project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to support the project financially and help us secure our future hires, you can do so using the &lt;a href="https://fund.godotengine.org/">Godot Development Fund&lt;/a> platform managed by &lt;a href="https://godot.foundation/">Godot Foundation&lt;/a>. There are also several &lt;a href="/donate">alternative ways to donate&lt;/a> which you may find more suitable.&lt;/p></description><category>Pre-release</category><guid>https://godotengine.org/article/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-2/</guid><dc:creator>Thaddeus Crews</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><image>https://godotengine.org/storage/blog/covers/dev-snapshot-godot-4-5-beta-2.webp</image></item></channel></rss>